export const Questions = [


    {
        "prompt": "Which Nigerian city is known as the 'Centre of Excellence'?",
        "OptionA": "Abuja",
        "OptionB": "Lagos",
        "OptionC": "Port Harcourt",
        "OptionD": "Enugu",
        "answer": "B"
    },
    

    {
        "prompt": "Which ethnic group is the largest in Nigeria?",
        "OptionA": "Yoruba",
        "OptionB": "Igbo",
        "OptionC": "Hausa",
        "OptionD": "Fulani",
        "answer": "C"
    },

    {
        "prompt": "What is the capital city of Nigeria?",
        "OptionA": "Lagos",
        "OptionB": "Abuja",
        "OptionC": "Kano",
        "OptionD": "Ibadan",
        "answer": "B"
    },
    

    {
        "prompt": "Which river is the longest in Nigeria?",
        "OptionA": "Niger River",
        "OptionB": "Benue River",
        "OptionC": "Osun River",
        "OptionD": "Ogun River",
        "answer": "A"
    },

    {
        "prompt": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "OptionA": "1950",
        "OptionB": "1960",
        "OptionC": "1970",
        "OptionD": "1980",
        "answer": "B"
    },

    {
        "prompt": "Who is the current Vice President of Nigeria?",
        "OptionA": "Atiku Abubakar",
        "OptionB": "Goodluck Jonathan",
        "OptionC": "Kashim Shettima",
        "OptionD": "Yemi Oshibajo",
        "answer": "C"
    },


    {
        "prompt": "Who is the first female Finance Minister of Nigeria?",
        "OptionA": "Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala",
        "OptionB": "Kemi Adeosun",
        "OptionC": "Zainab Ahmed",
        "OptionD": "Nenadi Usman",
        "answer": "A"
    },

    
    {
        "prompt": "What is the official language of Nigeria?",
        "OptionA": "Hausa",
        "OptionB": "Igbo",
        "OptionC": "Yoruba",
        "OptionD": "English",
        "answer": "D"
    },


    {
        "prompt": "Who was Nigeria's first Prime Minister?",
        "OptionA": "Obafemi Awolowo",
        "OptionB": "Ahmadu Bello",
        "OptionC": "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
        "OptionD": "Abubakar Tafawa Balewa",
        "answer": "D"
    },


    {
        "prompt": "Which Nigerian musician is known as the 'African Giant'?",
        "OptionA": "Wizkid",
        "OptionB": "Burna Boy",
        "OptionC": "Davido",
        "OptionD": "Tiwa Savage",
        "answer": "B"
    },


    {
        "prompt": "What is the name of Nigeria's national currency?",
        "OptionA": "Naira",
        "OptionB": "Cedi",
        "OptionC": "Rand",
        "OptionD": "Shilling",
        "answer": "A"
    },


    {
        "prompt": "Which Nigerian city is known as the 'Coal City'?",
        "OptionA": "Enugu",
        "OptionB": "Kano",
        "OptionC": "Owerri",
        "OptionD": "Calabar",
        "answer": "A"
    },


    {
        "prompt": "Which Nigerian author wrote the novel 'Things Fall Apart'?",
        "OptionA": "Wole Soyinka",
        "OptionB": "Chinua Achebe",
        "OptionC": "Chimamanda Adichie",
        "OptionD": "Buchi Emecheta",
        "answer": "B"
    },


    {
        "prompt": "What is the name of Nigeria's highest mountain?",
        "OptionA": "Mount Idanre",
        "OptionB": "Hill Zuma",
        "OptionC": "Jos Plateau",
        "OptionD": "Chappal Waddi",
        "answer": "D"
    },

    {
        "prompt": "Which Nigerian female artist collaborated with Beyonc√© on the song 'Brown Skin Girl'?",
        "OptionA": "Yemi Alade",
        "OptionB": "Simi",
        "OptionC": "Wizkid",
        "OptionD": "Teni",
        "answer": "C"
    }
    
        


    
]